I remember my really good friend my
really like my ace boon
she she used to hear me tell
stories and she would be like and she
she revealed this later she was like you
know I would say to myself she must be
leaving something out there's no way
this could have happened this way she
must be leaving something out until I
got kicked out that emy's
party what' you do to get kicked out the
Em's party damn we can't take you
nowhere what you do I go to a lot of
places cuz I'm lovable and people like
me and I'm delightful um I am delightful
what did you do I
arrived okay you arrived okay you're
inside no so here's how it went so
because Hollywood is just so inundated
with whiteness there was this
conglomeration of folks that came
together to say you know what we're
going to have a black emmies party cuz
you know have you been to the Emmy
parties I've never been to Emmy party so
like they're just you know they're just
very blah like just a bunch of people
sitting around
like am I right am I right oh my God
kren Kiren Kiren like that's the vibe um
but you know when we party we want to
have a little bit more fun to it you
know Cy nice um so what up Derek
so the in
20 18 was the first one where they had a
black em party so basically it's like
everybody who done been to all them
other parties come in this one yes
and I went to that party with Jill Scott
and one of the people that planned that
party was Issa raed publicist um Vanessa
Anderson so she was one of the planners
of the party but there's a bunch of
people involved in planning this party
correct so I show up with Jill and um
Jill's manager was like Hey you know can
we and I remember hearing Vanessa go
like oh come on Amanda mind you I'm like
I don't know what I'm doing wrong right
here like I'm just standing with Jo
Scott uh but nonetheless we came in the
party we had a great
time so but it and I said to Issa like I
don't know what's going on with your
publicist but like she she got something
wrong she got a problem with me and she
was like that's between y'all okay I
said well it's not really between y'all
cuz I don't have a problem with her
right but she seems to have a problem
with me and she was like that's none of
my business okay
okay so now next year is 2019 and it was
interesting because in 2018 it was
packed like a dick in front of that
place and 2019 there was like nobody
there but I was at the HBO party and
every black person I saw I would tell
them make sure you go to the black emies
party cuz I am about creating community
and I want us to be together right so I
pull up with my H girl catha and
Kendrick Samson who's on insecure you
know the show where I don't have any
friends yeah um so I pull up with
Kendrick Samson so we get to the door
and I learned later that she just is
white passing but this is a Mexican girl
but like she looked like a white girl
okay so she at the at the door for the
for the em for what kind of party emy's
black party there you go so she tells us
you can go in you can go in you can't go
in now I'm think she talking to my
friend because my friend is a realtor
right um and she says no you can't go in
and I said why can't I go in she says
you're just on the list to not be able
to go in now I had also been invited to
this party directly by Jesse Williams
right so Jesse Williams had texted me
and said please come to the black emy's
party right okay so I'm like all right
I'mma come I'mma come to the black Emy
party yeah of course like that's what I
am about so I come to the party and I'm
like okay
uh why am I not being let in
h Kendrick says I'm GNA go look I'm G to
go look around and see why you're not
being let
in well baby I'm not standing outside no
party right so I head out but then I'm
by just by this brother Joey Harris who
works with Janet Jackson Joey's like and
Joey's like one of these people who's
just always he's his disposition is just
always like glowing it's kind of like
Jordan right so he's like um where you
going I'm like oh they said I can't they
won't let me in the party he's like
absolutely not come on back we going to
get you in this party look so we come
back and so this is an example of
someone trying to protect and look out
right so he brings me back and he's like
why are you not letting her in the Party
by the way at this time time I'm hosting
bring the funny on NBC right there is a
billboard the size of a hotel two blocks
away with me and my co-stars on the show
Chrissy tan Jeff Foxworthy and um Keenan
Thompson and can I just put a pin in
this really quick to give them their
props I had a real hard time on insecure
and I'll get to that but being on this
show was so affirming because every
everyone there was so just happy to be
happy and I hadn't experienced that on
that set like from the showrunner to the
writers to my my stage manager Roger to
my co-stars like I just got to be myself
right and it really let me know it's not
you it's the
environment and I don't get to talk
enough about like the positive [ __ ]
because people are always so attracted
to the negative but I remember day one
Chrissy tan I we had to do rehearsals
for the first day and they had me in
these stilettos shining oh my God like I
would have had to go the PO yes the feet
were crying and it was I had an injury
from these [ __ ] stilettos and the
next day Chrissy Tegan brought a a foot
massage from um Sharper Image and left
it in my dressing room for the duration
of the shoot like that's the kind of
people you know just generous for no
reason right and we just had a blast we
had such a good time and I remember Jeff
Foxworthy one time they wanted us to do
this ad where we had to pass around a
drink and I don't drink so it's like I
don't mind drinks being around but like
me pretending like I drink a ain't my
job right so I was like I just don't
feel comfortable doing this now it
becomes a thing this is how I get label
difficult cuz I didn't get we didn't get
any prep for this but you need to go
along with whatever they give you didn't
you know that whatever they give you you
supposed to do no well when you're a
woman it's even more sh quit stirring up
trouble so
Jeff Foxworthy saw [ __ ] going left and
he stepped in and he said yeah I don't
feel comfortable with it either wow he
used his Fame his white manness you know
he used his disposition to just take the
heat off of me he said I got
you to this day I really want to do a
show with Jeff foxy we were just like
fish and talk [ __ ] like that's a goal I
want to do let me know if you want to
produce youever been fishing
I've been present while someone is
fishing but I have not been given a rod
so you hadn't had a rod or a pole in
your hand but I have I have dated men
from the south I have been present and
had crappy cooked for me yes oh okay so
yes so I think youd be more of a a Shore
fisherman you know on the land can't be
in the boat
Lord I'm I'm generally ask yeah yeah but
I'm saying we go we go we go baby yeah
we go baby step it's harder in the boat
than on the land yeah probably so really
cuz you're not as not as now
thought because I thought there were
more fish in the center they're more
fish yeah but when they go way out there
they they're normally fishing for a
particular type of fish like when you on
when you on the shore you fish with
anything to bite catfish crappy you know
uhhuh perch Vass but normally when you
go out you fish for you know maybe
you're trying to catch tuna you brino
something like that huh
tuna Snapper
yes okay I'm into it you know about fish
you just never actually had a rod in
your hand and like brought it in oh
so I am um I hyper fix a so I know a lot
about a lot of things because I become
immersed yes so like I'm a scuba diver
so I know a lot about fish and then at
one point it was like I'm going to learn
everything I know about dogs and now I'm
going to learn everything I need to know
about Game of Thrones I'm going to learn
everything I need to know about you know
uh NCAA football like I mean like but I
do know a lot about
fish so you say you so cuz I'm I'm in
the middle of a story and sometimes I
Veer off but I always come back cuz I
want to make sure we get to the your
insecure role so I just wanted to shout
that out because bring the funny was a
beautiful experience and it was super
super D super duper super duper dope so
when we're here and Joey Harris is
trying to get me in this party the white
girl says
again um well the white passing girl
says again yeah no she can't come to the
party so Joey's like we go inside and
figure out what's going
on again I'm not about to stand out here
right so I start to walk away again and
now Elijah Kelly comes out he's like hey
hey hey hey hey where you going I said
they they they not trying to let me in
this
party that I was invited to right by
Jesse Williams um did you attempt to
call
Jesse did I attempt to call Jesse I
texted him okay um but he's in a party
right you know so I texted him uh so
then Elijah is like well one of the
planners of the party so they can't stop
you they can't stop me from bringing you
in right so he starts to bring me in and
home girl grabs my arm but I remember
when I told you I've been in New Yorker
since I was 12 shake that off yeah lose
me yeah crazy so we go in the party and
I go and sit down no sorry I go in the
party I go by the bar my home girl goes
to the bathroom I'm standing by the bar
and a security guard approaches me uh oh
a security guard your size approaches me
and says hey um I'm going to have to ask
you to
leave and I said well why do why why why
why do I need to leave and he said
because um you're you're being asked to
leave I said well who's asking me to
leave he said well let me go find
out well why he well I mean you came and
say some they're asking you to leave and
you don't know who's asking me to leave
you got to go find out he was given an
order yeah so now he comes back and uh
he says Vanessa Anderson is asking you
to leave I said well you need to find
Vanessa and have her come tell me
herself is that Isa rais published
yes I said well you need to have Vanessa
come and find me and tell me
herself so he then leaves again and
comes back with three other
men and one of the men now it's a
brother and he's walking towards me
cursing so he's literally walking
towards me saying you need to get the
out of here you need to leave and I'm
like mind you I'm I'm dressing down
honey okay and he's like you need to
leave now cathia was in the bathroom
she's now just come up and I'm looking
around and I can see people
seeing right so I'm like why do I have
to leave cuz we said so so there's like
violent energy and language coming
towards you right
um I ain't no
sucker okay mhm
and but I'm also not stupid I can't
fight for a men so like I mean right
so
I the the first one who was kind he had
come up right here but then the other
three were right here so I have to
realize I've lost this fight so I pivot
to leave but I pivot really fast because
I'mma still say my mother piece so when
I pivot and I say I I pivot to go you I
guess they thought I was about to do
something so the white guy steps in
between me and the two the and the
brother and chest bumps me and throws me
back right so now this is an assault cuz
I hadn't raised my hand to do anything
to anybody so luckily I'm Nimble in a
heel so I I but now it's like you know
now I've been assaulted so your natural
response so I'm about to go Super Saiyan
on these mother it's Goku over here I'm
like
ah and I hear in one ear I hear the
security guard saying please please
Amanda don't do it and it it feels like
please missia don't do it don't be like
me Miss don't be like Miss Sophia and
then in the other ear I have my home
girl who's from the Bronx like what the
is going on this is some [ __ ] and
all I'm hearing
is but I look around and I see nobody
coming to my
Aid all these agents and people that I
see around now none of them are insecure
none of them are the actors from
insecure um but there's people whose
faces I still remember and they will not
get a hug in a either I just refused
somebody to hug the other day for this
um
and I realize like you you got to go so
we walk outside and the security guard
says to me you know I'm so sorry like
I'm just doing my job and I said I I
feel you but you have to ask
yourself is it worth doing a job that
makes you go against your moral
compass he was
like Dam so I hope he left that job cuz
he could tell that he was was in some he
was mixed up in some bull so we're in a
back
alley like waiting for a car and I'm
crying cuz this feels like you know I've
been humiliated and I didn't do nothing
and that was the night that me and my
home girl became super like that became
my sister because she was like when you
would tell me that [ __ ] would happen to
you I would think she must be keeping
something out right but I literally just
watched you do nothing you literally
just came somewhere you were invited
right and even though you tried to leave
multiple people said no you belong
here multiple people another person on
this team said you belong here so I'm
bringing you in here and then when I
tell the story on my Instagram and on my
my podcast it ends up getting turned
into this whole other thing of you don't
belong here Amanda seals doesn't belong
here and that's the thing that's a
narrative that that has come about like
been perpetuated yes I don't belong in
these places
and what ended up happening two days
later is that I got a call from
Issa and she called me and said um hey I
heard what happened this weekend um I
just want you to know I have nothing to
do with it um would you be willing to
talk to
Vanessa no I tried to talk to Vanessa at
the
party she two days too
late so I've never talked about this
publicly because it has always been
incredibly important to me to protect
Issa because I know that Issa is doing
something within this business that so
few people get to do and it's not
something I desire to do like I'm I'm
not interested in getting a $100 million
production deal like that's not a life
that I want for myself but I know that
her role is very important and so I've
always protected Issa um however there's
just been enough instances at this point
where I should have been protected by
Isa and I wasn't and one of my biggest
problems that we have discussed several
times in this interview is that I I
think people are going to show up for me
the way I show up for them and now it's
at a point where my protecting of Issa
has become turned on to me and something
that people are using against me there's
a whole narrative that is completely
false that people keep spinning they
keep saying you know that I'm this mean
girl on this set that I that I uh that I
harmed these people on this set I just
want to point out something very basic
how can I be a mean girl on a set that
ain't my
set how how it's your show you are my
boss I don't even have the capacity to
be the Mean Girl here cuz you can fire
me so there's no way for me to be a mean
girl in this situation and I know some
people that may buck up against like the
the confirmation bias that they've
created but it simply is the truth um
you know when I got to that show I had
had a show on issa's website on YouTube
I had my show get your life and when it
came out on her in on her YouTube
unfortunately the the the the Press
picked it up as Issa R's new show right
but I'm but she hadn't she didn't do
anything except put it on her site like
I put all my money into it I wrote it I
started it Etc and so I said hey you
know would you mind you know tweeting to
correct this and she just wouldn't um
she wouldn't promote any of the shows
you know and I just felt like that was
unfortunate but it didn't make me it
didn't change my my view of her
character like it just let me know like
okay this how she do business but in
that time her publicist was interacting
with me and was from just day one just
so aeric like just vitriolic for no
reason to the point where isa's business
manager had to say to the publicist like
can you please try and be kinder to
Amanda she's like a talent on our
channel do you and you have no reason
why she
would treat you
behave
so Issa says would you talk to Vanessa
no
I said sure you know why why who's my
boss who's my boss in this situation
well he is the boss and where do I have
to go back to work insecure so what's
the game you talked about you had to
play the
game but hold on but there was a
situation earlier Amanda where she that
ain't my business y'all need to handle
that now she want you to talk to her
you're good at math
you good at math
Sharpton Shannon sharp I'm just I'm just
saying because you like you can't spell
Sharpton without sharp
now man so okay you have so I take the
call you should have said I want to meet
face to face I want to look on one I
like to look on person my feelings were
hurt my feelings were hurt I just got
assaulted in a party for black people in
Hollywood mhm and I've been in Hollywood
longer than majority of the people in
this [ __ ] party right my feelings are
hurt okay you take the
call hello hi Manda this is Vanessa um I
just want you to know that um so none of
this has anything to do with Isa that's
the first thing she says none of this
has anything to do with Issa so I just
want you to know that but I do want you
to understand that it was me who kicked
you out the
party okay so um I just want you to know
that the reason I kicked you out the
party is because I don't like
you okay well that's all I need to know
there's nothing else for us to talk
about and I hang up she calls me back
immediately why' you hang up I said
because there's nothing else for us to
talk about she says don't you want to
know why I don't like you no not
actually actually I don't no I don't CU
it's none of my business I've never done
anything to you and for you to put Me In
Harm's Way off of literally nothing
means that I don't need to talk to you
about why you don't like me you need to
talk to your therapist about why you
don't like me and I hung up the phone
she called back no she called around she
starts a smear campaign
oh so this whole time your boss and I
don't like I I don't do the gossip thing
so have you ever had a conversation with
Issa about this sit about her publicist
you're saying Since the situation at any
point well I mean I had that one time
where I said to you yeah and she said
well that y'all need to work that out
that ain't got nothing to do with me so
now after this conversation with the
publicist and I and I get off the phone
um I start getting word that she is
going around to the different
Publications and different people
because it starts coming back to me and
she's going around saying that I was um
in danger of getting fired from insecure
which I honestly I don't even know if
that was true or not but I had never
that had never been brought to my
attention she starts going around saying
that I got in a fight at the party she
starts going around saying that I peed
on the
floor at the party what are you a puppy
I mean I got to move it to the side like
what are we talking about so let me ask
you this so well I feel like I'm going
to answer your question okay
so Issa then calls me again and says hey
I just want to know if this is going to
be a problem on set cuz now this is
going on for two weeks and
this going
viral in earlier in the conversation you
were like why do you care if people
don't who don't know you like are saying
mean things about
you and it's like I wish I had that and
I I'm at a point in my life where I'm
there
but it's really up when the pylon
happens and it has nothing to do with
reality like I don't even mind a pylon
if it's something I really did right
this situation I'm like how am I the
villain in this situation well you
shouldn't have gone to her party because
it was her party well it's not just her
party there's several people at the
party it's not like I crashed her baby
shower right um but also I'm looking at
Issa cuz it's like this is your
responsibility we are both your
employees and this is a part of
leadership this is the important part of
leadership and it's that's what makes
leadership so annoying is you got to
manage people yes you do and
personalities and it's it's a difficult
it's a very difficult task but it is
part for the course yes but that's why
you got the 100 million or whatever you
got is to manage your employees so said
you know listen I am not saying that
it's going to be a problem on set but I
do think it is a problem that you don't
feel that you need to step in and she
was like well then we just have a
difference in opinion like I just this
is this is between y'all this is between
y'all well if it was between us why did
you intervene and say I need to that
that she wanted to call I needed to talk
to her if you felt it was just between
us because you interjected yourself into
that if it's between two people I
shouldn't have interference from someone
else to say we need to get together the
two people people either she reaches out
to me or I reach out to her I don't need
you to intervene but you felt the need
to intervene in that but now you don't
feel it intervene to go any further the
intervention to go any
further oh
sorry so I'm also promoting my book
right so this hits me because now the
Press is cancelling so this is now
affecting me
professionally and I didn't do [ __ ]
right and I don't like you in my opinion
is not a sufficient reason
to sick four security guards on me and
remove me from a black space right which
also begs the question what the is a
black space cuz we we we we like to
claim that they're safe spaces and you
know that they're for us but at this
point black spaces are literally it's
just black faces right and that even is
you know something to do with this press
that I've been going through but to stay
on course
so now we have to go back to shooting
uncomfortable I'm uncomfortable and I
ain't even on sick and nobody's saying
nothing to me everybody knows cuz at
this time it's just the women shooting
everybody knows what's going on they
don't say nothing to
me and that's just fing mean it's mean
they don't say nothing to me and let me
tell you from the beginning I've been
trying with these ladies because I want
to make Community everywhere I go I done
invited them to my house they didn't
come I brought them gifts they said
thank I tried to plan a retreat they say
we don't want to go you know I I put I
created our group chat for the show I
created game nights for the show um
nobody participated I mean eventually
but like
reluctantly but I'm trying to do this
you know
um because I think that this is it's
like when I walked in and I was like I
feel like it's my role to make you feel
comfortable like I feel like that's my
way of of of getting around this thing
this stigma that people like to put on
me that ain't got [ __ ] to do with how I
really exist
okay
um
and in this situation now I'm publicly
now being like excoriated you got this
earthworm gy looking [ __ ] seris out
here talking about well you don't no one
likes you so that's why you weren't
invited what's hilarious about that is
that we were only in two scenes together
so this is not somebody that really
knows me but you know what the other
thing is Shannon Sharpton
W this is a brother who ended up having
a child with someone on the
show and when he had the child there was
rumors that were going around that he
was not um claiming the child and so
these people have started talking about
it but the people that are talking about
ain't my people I'm not involved in it
but I hear it cuz we on set right and
then he come around and is hey
I don't like like
that I don't like like that it's not
honest so even though that's not my boy
I pull him to the side I say
Pete people out here are talking about
you behind your back about this
situation Street's talking and I said
listen this is a small business so at
the end of the day if you are this
child's father I think you should
exclaim it to the rooftops if you are
not claim if you are you don't want to
claim this child I would like for you to
just consider rethinking that because as
somebody with a father that did not show
up for me I really feel like she would
really benefit from having a father in
her life MH and he was like well why
ain't nobody coming to me I said I'm
literally coming to you right now and
you ain't even my peoples but I don't
think it's fair that you're being talked
about behind your back by people that
you think are your peoples he said well
you know thank you for that that's the
same [ __ ] that fixed his mouth to jump
on the bandwagon of we hate
Amanda because it was a bandwagon and he
want to be seen he thought maybe he was
punished he thought he was going to get
an extra right he thought he was going
to get an extra scene or
something so now we're on set and I I
finally say to Esa so were you just not
going to talk about this because it's
now going on for three weeks and my
mental health is suffering okay
and I just what I just it was a tough
time
and um she's like well you know like
what what do you want to talk about I
said listen like the this was a terrible
experience right this was
terrible I like literally cried like
face to face with her like this is
terrible and she's like this is the
first time she finally says like well
I'm sorry that happened to you it took
three conversations mhm and I said well
you know I'd like to talk to you further
because I need you to speak to Vanessa
she is trying to ruin my career
she's like I don't think
so like she's trying to ruin my like I
so I bring her into the room I bring her
into my trailer and I had to do another
48 Laws of Power I sat her on a higher
plane than myself so that she can feel
as the queen and in this setting she is
the queen right and I said you
know I don't need nothing from you so I
don't have a reason to lie to you but
the people that work for you like in
close quarters as whose names are really
attached to you they will lie to
you and I had to convince her that like
this is really happening like I'm not
making this up and even if it's turns
out to be not happening I still need you
to speak to her to deduce what it is
what is or isn't right so then she she
finally went and spoke to her um but the
damage is done right because now you see
how every few years this becomes a thing
and it was started from a lie right it
was started from a lie and you know it's
not about convincing people because I
don't need to convince nobody and
nothing but I just don't ever feel
comfortable with people forming opinions
not based on truth want to join Club sh
Shay become an official member by
hitting that subscribe button where you
never know who's going to be joining us
for drinks and conversation don't be
late to the party because you know we
like to do something before two
something